Pallavi Patil

UI Designer

UI designer born and raised in India with a background in Architecture. I have experience in designing, detailing and sensitivity to user needs which helped while learning UI designing. As a designer, my main aim is to create an aesthetically appealing User Interface which is functional and easy to use.



pallavi.patil06@gmail.com



+1631-374-4371



Austin, TX

EXPERIENCE

Summer Camp for kids, Austin —Creative team

June2020 - October2020

Volunteer to conceptualise a creative Summer camp for kids in covid situation through a digital platform. Responsible for in concept, costume and designing prop, video editing.

Freda's Kitchen, Austin — Indian Chef

August 2019 - March2020

Was part of the International cook team, representing India for unique private culinary experiences and corporate team building events centered around authentic ethnic cuisine. Responsible for crafting authentic Indian menu, teaching and helping teams to execute dishes.

J Kokolakis Contracting, Long Island — Asst. Project Manager

November 2008 - October 2010

Assisted Manager in preparing RFI, Submittals, Change orders, Contracts and site inspection. Support communication between the project team, clients, vendors, engineers, consultants, and building officials.

RSP Architects, Hyderabad— Architect

November 2006- January 2008

Involved in the preliminary design process of layout and units of IT projects. Prepared concept design & presentation of projects for Client approvals. Developed detailed design and working drawings upon approval of the concept design. Coordinated with different service consultants. Worked as a team and also individual to deliver projects in stipulated time.

SKILLS

Competitor research
User research
Design Process
User Persona
User Flow Diagrams
Wireframing
MoodBoards
Style Guides
Prototype
Usability Testing
Branding
Mockups

Tools

Sketch
Photoshop
InVision
Flinto
Balsamiq
Usability Hub
Basic Html
Basic CSS
Javascript

Education

CareerFoundry
Certification in UI Design, 2021

University of MumbaiBachelors of Architecture, 2002